A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office Files of Louis Winnick FA601
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subject Files, 1950-1974; III
  - Ford Foundation Subject Files, 1955-1974; 1
    - Electoral Process Meeting -- Committee on Electoral Study and Reform Interim Report (1 of 2), 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Electoral Process Meeting -- Committee on Electoral Study and Reform Memoranda, Meeting Minutes (2 of 2), 1969 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Federal National Mortgage Association -- Ford Foundation PRI to Mortgage Opportunities Inc., Memoranda Re: Loan Correspondent Program, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Fiscal, New York City -- Memoranda Re: Ford Foundation Involvement in NYC Fiscal Study, 1963 September 11 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Ford Foundation -- "The Arts and the Ford Foundation: 1969" (report), 1968 December (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Ford Foundation -- Committee on the Role of Women -- Memoranda Re: Drake-Beam Survey, Ford Foundation Policy on Women (1 of 3), 1970 June-1971 February (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Ford Foundation -- Committee on the Role of Women -- Memoranda Re: Drake-Beam Survey, Ford Foundation Policy on Women (2 of 3), 1971 February (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Ford Foundation -- Committee on the Role of Women -- Memoranda Re: Drake-Beam Survey, Ford Foundation Policy on Women (3 of 3), 1971 March-June (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation -- Drug Abuse Meetings -- Notes, Reports, Meeting Book, 1968 June 6-7 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Ford Foundation -- Equal Opportunities for Minority Groups -- Paper and Program Statement for Board Meeting, 1967 June (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Ford Foundation -- Exploratory Conference on the Measurement of Negro Social and Economic Mobility -- Transcript, Agenda (1 of 2), Sep 24, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Ford Foundation -- Exploratory Conference on the Measurement of Negro Social and Economic Mobility -- Background (2 of 2), 1963 September 24 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Ford Foundation -- "A Ford Foundation Role in American Indian Development" (report), 1968 December (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Ford Foundation -- "The Foundation's Responsibilities to New York City: Four Alternative Means of Payment" (report), 1968 March (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Ford Foundation -- Leadership Development Program -- Report, Correspondence, etc. Re: FAP to Promote Urban Executive Leadership, 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Ford Foundation -- "The Legislative Internship Program: A Report to the Ford Foundation" (report), 1968 October 1 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Ford Foundation -- Management Costs Information Paper and Recommended Budgets, 1968 September (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Ford Foundation -- Memoranda, Reports from Other Programs Re: Ford Foundation Policy, Grantees, Program Development (1 of 2), 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Ford Foundation -- Memoranda, Reports from Other Programs Re: Ford Foundation Policy, Grantees, Program Development (2 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Ford Foundation -- National Affairs -- Administrative Budget FY 1969, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation -- National Affairs -- Budget FY 1970 -- Working Papers, Draft Budget, Narratives, Notes, Memoranda (1 of 2), 1969 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Ford Foundation -- National Affairs -- Budget FY 1970 -- Working Papers, Draft Budget, Narratives, Notes, Memoranda (2 of 2), 1969 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Ford Foundation -- National Affairs -- Finance Committee -- Memoranda and Data on Support for Dependent Organizations, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Ford Foundation -- National Affairs -- Program Budget Request FY 1968, 1967 June (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Ford Foundation -- National Affairs -- Program Management Budgets FY 1968-1973 -- Manpower Projections, Memoranda, 1967-1972 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Ford Foundation -- National Affairs -- Program Planning Budget FY 1971 -- Planning Paper, Memoranda, 1970-1974 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Ford Foundation -- National Affairs -- Program Planning Budgets FY 1972-1973 -- Budget, Memoranda, DAP List, 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Ford Foundation -- National Affairs -- Retreat, Tarrytown, NY -- Memoranda Re: Social Development, Urban and Metropolitan Development, Report on Drug Abuse, 1968 February 6-7 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Ford Foundation -- National Affairs -- Staff Meetings -- Memoranda Re: Environmental Institute, Gray Areas, Active Grants, 1966-1970 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Ford Foundation -- New Building Zoning Information, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Ford Foundation -- "Program-Directed Investments: A Wider View of Philanthropy" (report), 1968 March (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation -- "Program-Directed Investments" (report), 1968 June (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Affairs Current Projects -- Report, List, 1963-1965 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Affairs Gray Areas Program -- Review Paper, List of Project Directors, 1964 September (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Affairs Memoranda Re: Housing, Civil Rights, Relationship to Government Programs, etc., 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Affairs Memoranda Re: Other Programs (Urban Centers, Latin America Grants, etc.), 1964-1966 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Affairs Memoranda Re: Quarterly Grant Payments, Staff Announcements, Changes in Travel and Study Award Program, 1964-1966 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Affairs Program Planning Budget for FY 1966-1968, 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Affairs Program Planning Budget for FY 1967-1969, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Affairs Staff Meetings -- Agenda, Minutes, 1964-1966 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Policy Committee -- Meeting Agenda and Notes, Grant Proposals, Memoranda Re: Proposals, Ford Foundation Policy (1 of 2), 1972 January-October (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Policy Committee -- Meeting Agenda and Notes, Grant Proposals, Memoranda Re: Proposals, Ford Foundation Policy (2 of 2), 1972 October-December (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Policy Committee -- Meeting Agenda, Grant Proposals, Memoranda Re: Proposals (1 of 3), 1973 January-February (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Policy Committee -- Meeting Agenda, Grant Proposals, Memoranda Re: Proposals (2 of 3), 1973 March-September (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Ford Foundation -- Public Policy Committee -- Meeting Agenda, Grant Proposals, Memoranda Re: Proposals (3 of 3), 1973 September-December (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Ford Foundation -- Remarks at the National Conference on Crime and Urban Crisis Sponsored by National Council on Crime and Delinquency by McGeorge Bundy, 1969 February 4 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Ford Foundation -- "The Role of Computer Technology in Solving Urban Problems" (report), 1967 August 7 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Ford Foundation -- "Social Mobility of the American Negro" (report), 1964 June 4 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Ford Foundation -- Southern Programs -- Memoranda Re: Meetings of the Southern Growth Policies Board, VEP Report, Review of Ford Foundation Programs, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Ford Foundation -- Travel Committee -- Memoranda, Recommendations, Background for Revisions to Ford Foundation Travel Policy, 1966-1971 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation -- UN Delegates' Visit to the Foundation -- Notes for Talk, Correspondence, Memoranda, 1969 March 29 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Ford Foundation -- "U.S. Manpower Policy and Where the Foundation Fits In" (report), with Sviridoff Cover Memoranda, 1968 December (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Ford Foundation -- World Urbanization Survey -- Memoranda, Reports, Background on FAP, Urban Grants, Site Visits (1 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Ford Foundation -- World Urbanization Survey -- Memoranda, Reports, Background on FAP, Urban Grants, Site Visits (2 of 2), 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Harvard-MIT Joint Center for Urban Studies -- Memoranda, Notes, 1965 March 25 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - House Select Committee on Government Research -- Statement by Henry T. Heald on Federal Research Programs and Grants, Memoranda Re: Suggested Inclusions to Statement, 1963 October 16-November 21 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Housing and Development Administration Citizens Advisory Committee -- Certificate of Appointment, 1968 March 12 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Housing and Development Administration Citizens Advisory Committee -- Meeting Minutes and Agenda with Background on Housing and Urban Development Act of 1969, Rent Stabilization Law, Tenants Rights Movement (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Housing and Development Administration Citizens Advisory Committee, 1971 February-October (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Housing and Development Administration Citizens Advisory Committee, 1971 November-1972 April (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Housing and Development Administration Citizens Advisory Committee, 1972 May-November (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Housing and Redevelopment Board -- Middle-Class Housing Discussion Points, Memoranda Re: Mitchell-Lama Program, Meeting Minutes, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Housing and Redevelopment Board -- Reports and Recommendations on New York Housing Policy, 1961-1966 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Housing and Redevelopment Board -- Task Force on Middle-Income Housing and Mitchell-Lama Task Force -- Recommendations, Report, Background, 1966-1967 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Housing and Urban Development -- Non-Profit Urban Development Corporation -- Background, Correspondence with Hortense W. Gabel, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - India Housing Project -- Association for India's Development (AID) -- Survey Report, Bibliography, Organization Chart, etc., 1964 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - India Housing Project -- Calcutta Metropolitan Development (CMD) Housing Team -- Correspondence, Proposal, CMD Plan, 1965-1966 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - India Housing Project -- Correspondence Re: Project, Staff, etc., 1964-1967 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - India Housing Project -- Housing Ministers' Conference, Chandigarh, India -- Agenda, Notes, Suggestions from State Governments, 1964 December 29-31 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - India Housing Project -- Report, Proposal, Background, 1958-1964 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - "India's Urban Housing: A Report to the Ford Foundation" with Appendix, 1965 January (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Institute of Race Relations -- Site Visit Report, Correspondence, Memoranda Re: Internal Strife, 1971-1973 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Manheim, Uriel -- Memoranda Re: Housing Removal Study, Phoenix Development Fund, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Mayor's Task Force on the Constitutional Convention -- Meeting Minutes, Testimony, Draft Laws (1 of 2), 1960-1967 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Mayor's Task Force on the Constitutional Convention -- Meeting Minutes, Testimony, Draft Laws (2 of 2), 1960-1967 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Minority Entrepreneurship -- Proposals and Background Paper on Promoting Minority-Owned Businesses, Directory of Organizations Concerned with Minority Business Development, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous -- Correspondence Re: Urban Planning, Program Budget Conference, Census Figures, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous -- Correspondence Re: HUD Secretary Visit, Urbanization Seminar, etc., 1966 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Model Cities Program -- Memoranda, Background on Federal Model Cities Act, 1966 March 14-August 15 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials -- Request to Publish Winnick Article, Research and Statistics Committee Meeting Minutes, Background, 1957-1962 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials Research Committee -- National Conference, Ford Urban Studies Workshop (1 of 4), 1961 January-September (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials Research Committee -- National Conference, Recommendations (2 of 4), 1961 October-December (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials Research Committee -- Demonstration Project for Relocation Assistance, Particularly for Elderly, Proposal, Progress Report (3 of 4), 1962 January-March (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials Research Committee -- Correspondence Re: Research Studies, Ontario Conference, Philadelphia Study Tour, etc. (4 of 4), 1962 April-December (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - National Association of Intergroup Relations Officials -- Correspondence and Progress Reports Re: Housing Proposal, 1961-1963 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - National Institute of Public Affairs -- Draft Report Assessment, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Negro Migration -- "The City and the Negro," Fortune, Charles E. Silberman, 1962 March (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Neighborhood Commons Project, Harry C. Harris -- Correspondence Re: Proposal, Background, Clipping, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - New York City Planning Commission -- Correspondence Re: Urban Renewal, Conferences, etc., 1956-1959 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - New York Urban League -- Site Visit Itinerary, Background, 1966 August 24 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - "Organized Self-Help Housing in the United States: Problems and Prospects" (report), 1964 July 15 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Real Estate Board of New York -- Address to Housing Projects Committee on Private Enterprise and Urban Proplems, Correspondence, 1968 May 9 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Rent Control -- Memoranda Re: Study of Rent Control, Background, 1963-1964 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Task Force on Middle-Income Housing -- Draft, Interim Report, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Urban Design -- Correspondence Re: Requests for Ford Foundation Support for Urban Design Classes, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Urban Extension Program -- Summaries of Grantees' Programs and Achievements, Working Paper, 1963-1966 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Urban Extension Program -- Correspondence, Conference Transcript, Recommended Grant Action, Notes, 1963-1966 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Vice President Hubert Humphrey Meeting -- Memoranda and Notes on Federal Monies in an Urban Complex, 1969 March 7 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Woodroofe, Philip B. -- Correspondence and Clippings on Being Fired for Founding Community Civic League to Better Interracial Relations, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Subject Files Prior to Ford Foundation, 1950-1963; 2
    The files in this subseries predate Winnick's time at the Ford Foundation. These subject files were created during his work with one of the following entities: the Institute for Urban Land Use and Housing Studies at Columbia University (1950-1955), the New York City Planning Commission, the Temporary State Commission on Economic Expansion (1959-1961), or the New York City Housing and Redevelopment Board (1961-1963).
    - Reprints of Articles, 1959-1960 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Pittsburgh Regional Planning Association - Design for Economic Study of the Pittsburgh Metropolitan Region, November 1959
      A Research Proposal for A Review of Urban Renewal Policies
      The Upper Midwest Economic Study: A Research Prospectus, prepared by James M. Henderson, January 25, 1960
    - Office of Transportation - Information on the Mass Transportation Demonstration Grant Program (pamphlet), undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Work Program Notes, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - World Trade Center: A Proposal for the Port of New York, Downtown Lower Manhattan Association, Inc. (publication), 1960 January 27 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Downtown Economists Club, 1956-1960 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - J. B. Cullingworth, 1959-1960 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Consumer Expenditure Study - Ivan Friend, University of Pennsylvania, Wharton School, 1953-1959 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Joint Economic Report and Economic Report of the President (publications), 1955-1957 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Consumer Expenditures Study, 1953-1956 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Paul Ylvisaker, 1959-1960 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Social Science Research Council and Russell Sage Foundation - Reports, 1956-1960 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Housing: Federal Legislation, 1955-1959 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Long Island's Transportation: Resources and Needs, Charles E. Stonier, Hofstra College Bureau of Business and Community Research (report), 1957 December (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Highways and Rapid Transit, 1954-1960 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Effects of Reductions in Building Bulk on Apartment Rents, 1959 August 20 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Metropolitan Chicago: An Economic Profile, Ezra Solomon and Zarko Bilbija (report), 1958 October (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Working Denver: An Economic Analysis by the Denver Planning Office (report), 1953 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Federal Reserve Bulletin, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      charts and graphics regarding industrial production
    - James Felt and Company Newsletters, 1957-1960 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Professor Ernest Fisher (Columbia University), 1955-1959 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - United States Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics - New Housing Characteristics, 1952-1956 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Housing and Urban Development Board - Section 221 Housing, 1960 July 5 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Housing - Veterans Administration, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Winnick's Personal Letters, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 7-8)
    - Housing - Racial Integration, 1957-1959 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Housing - New Starts, 1950-1959 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Federal Housing Authority - Monthly Reports, 1960-1961 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Review of Workmen's Compensation in New York State: Report of the Governor's Workmen's Compensation Review Committee (report), 1962 December (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Low Income Families in New York State in 1949, Daniel Creamer, State of New York Interdepartmental Committee on Low Incomes, 1957 September (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - The Relation of Family Status to Income and to Participation in the Labor Force - New York State, New York State Department of Labor, 1960 January (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - The Problems of Low Incomes: A Progress Report to the Governor by the New York State Interdepartmental Committee on Low Incomes, 1958 February (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Income: Census Surveys, 1955-1959 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Japanese Delegation, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Temporary State Commission on Economic Expansion, 1957-1959 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Public Housing, 1950-1960 (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
    - Federal Reserve Operations in the Money and Government Securities Markets, Robert V. Roosa, 1956 July (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Winnick's Case for a Changing Attitude Toward Housing: Comment, Jack Guttentag (pamphlet), 1956 May (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Institute of Transportation and Traffic Engineering - University of California, 1958-1963 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha, 1961-1963 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - International Reports (annual reports and pamphlets), 1961-1962 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Joint Council on Economic Education - Newsletters, 1961-1963 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Journal of Housing, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1957-1960 (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Speeches and Writings, 1957-1967; IV
  Dr. Winnick's speeches and writings primarily concern the topic of urban development. Several articles published in scholarly journals pre-date Dr. Winnick's time at Ford; the earliest is "Mortgage Credit in Perspective," co-authored with Ramsey Wood and published in the May 1956 issue of The Journal of Finance. Several drafts of articles dated later appear to have been written "on spec" and there is no indication they were ever published. The one writing not related to urban renewal or housing is an article containing Dr. Winnick's comments on the New York State economy and the state constitution during the New York State constitutional convention of 1967. It was published in the Proceedings of the Academy of Political Science in January, 1967.
  - "Mortgage Credit in Perspective," Journal of Finance, Ramsey Wood and Louis Winnick, 1956 May (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - "The Burden of the Residential Mortgage Debt," Journal of Finance, Louis Winnick, 1956 May (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - "Establishment of an Economist Service for the City of New York" (proposal), Louis Winnick and Lawrence Kaplan, 1957 December 11 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - "Investment Prospects in Urban Renewal," National Association of Mutual Savings Banks Annual Convention, Atlantic City, NJ, 1959 May 18 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - "Once More: Capital Formation in Residential Real Estate," Journal of Political Economy, Leo Grebler, David M. Blank and Louis Winnick, 1959 December (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - "Demand Factors in Urban Renewal," Appraisal Digest, Louis Winnick, 1960 January-March (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - "Economic Questions in Urban Redevelopment," 73rd Meeting of the American Economic Association, St. Louis, MO (Reprinted in American Economic Review, May 1961, 1960 December 28 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - "Facts and Fictions in Urban Renewal," in Ends and Means of Urban Renewal: Papers from the Philadelphia Housing Association's Fiftieth Anniversary Forum, 1961 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - "Financing the Rebuilding of Our Cities," Address to American Finance Association, New York, NY, 1961 December 29 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - "Rental Housing," Conference on Savings and Residential Financing Proceedings, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - "The Apartment House Market in the Sixties," 18th Annual Conference for Senior Executives in Mortgage Banking, New York University, 1963 January 17 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - "Ford Foundation Support for Research in Urban Transportation: The RAND Project and Other Possible Ventures" (report), John A. Perkins, Wayne E. Thompson and Louis Winnick, 1963 March 8 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - "Technological Changes in Urban Transportation," Space, Science and Urban Life Conference, Dunsmuir House, Oakland, CA, 1963 March 27-30 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - "The Current Status of City Planning: Prescription v. Public Choice," Address to Students and Faculty of MIT Dept. of City and Regional Planning, 1963 May 1 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - "Rental Housing Problems for Private Investment," United States Savings and Loan League 6th Annual Conference on Savings and Residential Finance, Chicago, IL, 1963 May 9-11 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - "Toward a More Livable Urban Environment" (discussion paper), 1963 July 19 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - "Social and Economic Questions in Urban Transportation," Urban Transportation Conference, Andover, NH, 1963 August 26 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - "The Planner Looks at Poverty and Race -- Or Does He?" American Institute of Planners, Milwaukee, WI, 1963 October 30 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Speech on the Role of the Ford Foundation in Dealing with the Problems of Urban Areas, Conference on Urban Affairs, Long Island University, 1964 March 7 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - "Review of the Urban Extension Program" (report), 1964 May 11 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - "Urban Land Value: A Neglected Subject," Conference on Regional Planning, Ditchley Park, England, 1964 July 19-21 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - "Place Prosperity v. People Prosperity" (draft report), 1964 December 30 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Louis Winnick Review of Housing: The Cooperative Way, 1965 February 24 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - "Subcommittee Report on HOPE Policy" (Re: Franklin Plaza Housing Development), Louis Winnick and Howard Sunshine, 1965 March 8 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - "Housing and Urban Development: The Private Foundation's Role," Council on Foundation 16th Annual Conference, 1965 May 21 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - "Comments on Richard Muth's Paper on Intra-Metropolitan Population Distribution," Delivered to the Conference on Investment Behavior, Madison, WI, 1965 June 10 (Box 23, Folder 26)